<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./value_filter.png" type="QuickForm" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Value Filter Definition</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Defines a filter definition to the input table and provides an interactive value filter on nominal columns.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>A value filter which can be used to trigger interactive filter events in a layout of views (e.g. the 
				WebPortal). The node appends a filter definition to the table spec.</p>
			<p>Only view nodes downstream of this node can receive interactive filter events.</p>
			<p>Note that the filter uses the possible values set on a nominal column's domain as configuration. To 
			ensure the values are reflected and sorted correctly the <i>Domain Calculator</i> and/or 
			<i>Edit Nominal Domain</i> nodes can be used beforehand.</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
        	<option name="Show Label">
        		Displays the column name as a label below or besides the slider. Use the <i>Custom</i> option to define 
        		an arbitrary label.
        	</option>
			<option name="Filter Column">
				Select the column to apply the filter definition to. The domain of possible values of the column is used
				to configure the filter. 
			</option>
			<option name="Default Values">
				Select the default values to be used for filtering from the possible values of the chosen filter 
				column. If <i>Single Values</i> is selected only the first value in the includes list will be present on
				the filter.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Filter">
			<option name="Merge With Existing Filter Definitions (Table)">
        		Check this setting to keep any pre-existing filter definitions on the output table. If not set only 
        		this node's filter definition is present on the output table.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Merge With Existing Filter Definitions (Model Port)">
        		Check this setting to keep any pre-existing filter definitions on the model output port. If not set 
        		only this node's filter definition is present on the output model.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Multiple / Single Values">
        		Choose multiple to be able to select multiple nominal values for filtering and single if only one value
        		should be part of the filter at any given time. Depending on the selection here the type field will 
        		offer different options for the display of the filter in the view.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Type">
        		Select the display type of the filter. Depending on the selection of multiple / single values, different
        		options are offered.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Limit number of visible options">
          		By default the List and Twinlist components adjust their height to display all possible choices without
          		a scroll bar. If this option is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in
          		case there is too many. The setting is available only for the List or Twinlist selection type.</option>
        	<option name="Number of visible options">
            	A number of options visible in the List or Twinlist component without a vertical scroll bar. 
            	Changing this value will also affect the component's height. Notice that for Twinlist the height cannot
            	be less than the overall height of the control buttons in the middle. The setting is available only for
            	List or Twinlist selection type.
        	</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Value Filter">
    	Select nominal values for interactive filtering.
    </interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Table">
			Input table which contains at least one nominal column with domain including possible values set, which 
			is used to control the filter view.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Table with Filter Definition">
			Input table with filter definition appended to the selected column.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Filter Definition">
			Filter definition applied to the selected column.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
