<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="quickform_value_select.png" type="QuickForm">
    <name>Value Selection QuickForm (legacy)</name>

    <shortDescription>
      Takes a data table and a selected column and returns a variable with the 
      selected value from this column.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Takes a data table and a selected column and returns a variable 
              with the selected value from this column. The selection can also
              be controlled from a quickfrom (WebPortal).
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Label">
          A descriptive label that will be shown in, for instance the web port.
        </option>
        <option name="Description">
          Some lines of description that will be shown in the remote control 
          form, for instance by means of a tooltip.
        </option>
        <option name="Weight">
          A weight value that influences the position of the component in
          the final layout. Lighter elements will be placed at the top, whereas
          heavier items will be placed nearer the bottom. The value is relative
          to the weights of the other components in the workflow (absolute 
          value is not relevant, only the relative comparison to other
          elements).
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Name">
          Variable identifier.
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Value">
          Variable value containing the select column names.
        </option>
        <option name="Column Selection">
          Column Selection panel to select a single column from.
        </option>
        <option name="Lock Column">
          If selected the column is locked and cannot be selected in WebPortal wizard execution.
        </option>
        <option name="Value Selection">
          Value Selection panel to select a single value from.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">
            A table to select a values from a column. 
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
            Variable output (string) with the selected value name.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
