<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./configuration_credentials.png"
	type="Configuration" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>Credentials Configuration</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Provides a credentials configuration option to an encapsulating component's dialog.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Outputs an credentials flow variable with a set value from a component's dialog.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
			A descriptive label that will be shown in the dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Description">
			Some lines of description that will be shown for instance in the node description of the component 
			exposing a dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">
			Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution).
			This will also be the name of the exported flow variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Username">
			The username.
		</option>
		<option name="Password">
			The password.
		</option>
		<option name="Username label">
			A custom label which is displayed for the username input field. This enables the utilization of various
			login methods. Defaults to "User" if no label is provided.
		</option>
		<option name="Password label">
			A custom label which is displayed for the password input field. This enables the utilization of various
			login methods. Defaults to "Password" if no label is provided.
		</option>
		<option name="Prompt user name in component dialog">
			Whether the username should be rendered as a separate field in the configuration dialog of a component.
			If unset the username field will not be shown and the output will always the pre-configured username.
		</option>
		<option name="Save password in configuration (weakly encrypted)">
			Whether the password should be saved with the workflow. Note that, if saved, the password can be revealed
			with modest effort by looking at the encryption algorithm used in KNIME's (open) source code. 
			If the password is not saved (option not set) the user will be prompted for the password when the workflow 
			is opened unless the node is already saved executed. In the latter case the password is not prompted 
			assuming downstream consumer nodes, e.g. a DB reader, are also executed and no longer need the
			credentials. In such cases (resetting and) executing a downstream node will fail as the password is not
			part of the credentials object passed from this node into the workflow - a re-configuration of this node
			is required.
		</option>
		<option name="Use KNIME Server Login (when run on server)">
			If the node is executed as part of a job on the KNIME Server Web Portal the password is populated with 
			the user credentials from the logged-in user.
			Please note that this option is not supported if your KNIME Server is configured to use single sign-on 
			(SSO) via OAuth/OIDC.
		</option>
		<option name="Don't render input fields">
			When the server login and password are used it might be desirable to not display any input fields. 
			When checking this option the component will not display, but user name and password are still retrieved 
			from server login credentials.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
			Variable output (credentials) with the given variable defined.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
