<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./configuration_fileUpload.png" type="QuickForm" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Local File Browser Configuration</name>

	<shortDescription>
	   Allows selecting a local file and exposing it using a flow variable.
	   Variable output representing the file path as variable. In case an absolute file path is selected the node
          will populate two variables: one representing the path and one representing the URL. If a URL is selected
          as default file only the URL variable is defined.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Allows selecting a local file and exposing it using a flow variable.
				Variable output representing the file path as variable. In case an absolute
				file path is selected the node will populate two variables: one representing the path and one
				representing the URL. If a URL is selected as default file only the URL variable is defined.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
			A descriptive label that will be shown in the dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Description">
			Some lines of description that will be shown for instance in the node description of the component exposing
			a dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution).
			This will also be the name of the exported flow variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Valid File Extensions">
			A list of file extensions that is used as filter in the
			file browser (not only the one in the "Default File" option but also
			in a remote file browser), e.g. ".csv,.csv.gz" will filter for
			files ending with ".csv" or ".csv.gz". Leave empty to accept any file.
		</option>
		<option name="Default File">
			The file that will be used during design time, i.e. when no file is provided by a component dialog.
			<br />
			It is possible to enter a URL here. This can be useful if a default file is to be addressed with
			the knime:// protocol (e.g. knime://knime.workflow/../data/file.csv) or if the file is present on a remote 
			server.
		</option>
		<option name="Timeout">
			The time in seconds after which the connection times out. The timeout is used when testing the existence of 
			default files. The default is set to 1 second and should be sufficient in most cases.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
			Variable output representing the file path as variable. In case an absolute file path is selected the node
			will populate two variables: one representing the path and one representing the URL. If a URL is selected
			as default file only the URL variable is defined.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
