<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./heatmap.png" type="Visualizer"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">

	<name>Heatmap (JavaScript)</name>
	<shortDescription>A node which creates a heatmap view using Javascript.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node displays the given input table as an interactive
				heatmap.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules
				into a single string and set it as a flow variable 'customCSS' in
				the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available
				classes and their description on our
				<a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>
				.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Label column">
				A column whose values will be used as the labels
				for the heatmap's rows. By default, the row IDs are used as labels.
			</option>
			<option name="Image column">
				A column of SVG images, which will appear when
				hovering over a row label. This field can only be modified if one or
				more SVG image columns are available. If not, a column cannot be
				selected and no image will be displayed when hovering over a row
				label.
			</option>
			<option name="Columns to display">
				Select the columns to display in the heatmap.
			</option>
			<option name="Minimum value">
				The minimum value for the color gradient to map to. If
				<i>Custom</i>
				is selected, a custom value may be entered. Columns without defined
				minimum values will not be used when computing the minimum.
			</option>
			<option name="Maximum value">
				The maximum value for the color gradient to map to. If
				<i>Custom</i>
				is selected, a custom value may be entered. Columns without defined
				maximum values will not be used when computing the maximum.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="View Configuration">
			<option name="Image width in pixels">
				The width, in pixels, of the output SVG image. If
				"Resize view to fill window" is not selected, this is also the
				static width of the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Image height in pixels">
				The height, in pixels, of the output SVG image.
				If "Resize view to fill window" is not selected, this is also the
				static height of the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Create image at outport">
				If checked, an SVG image will be produced as
				output.
			</option>
			<option name="Show warnings in view">
				If checked, warning messages will be displayed in
				the view when they occur.
			</option>
			<option name="Resize to window">
				Setting this option resizes the view to the
				available area of the window. If disabled the view size is static
				according to the set width and height.
			</option>
			<option name="Display full screen button">
				Displays a button enabling full screen mode.
			</option>
			<option name="Chart title" optional="true">
				The title of the graph
				shown above the generated image. If left blank, no title will be
				shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Chart subtitle" optional="true">
				The subtitle of the
				graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no subtitle
				will be shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Show tool tips">
				If selected, tool tips containing additional
				information will be displayed when hovering over a cell within the
				heatmap view.
			</option>
			<option name="Use discrete gradient">
				If checked, a discrete gradient will be used to
				color the heatmap. If not, a continuous gradient is used.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of colors">
				If using a discrete gradient, this is the number
				of discrete points to used. A minimum of three colors is required,
				and the number must be odd.
			</option>
			<option name="Select gradient colors">
				The three base colors used to define the
				gradient.
			</option>
			<option name="Select color for missing values">
				Sets the color used to represent missing values
				in the heatmap.
			</option>
			<option
				name="Select a color for values greater than the range maximum">
				Sets the color used to represent values above the specified
				maximum.
			</option>
			<option
				name="Select a color for values less than the range minimum">
				Sets the color used to represent values below the specified
				minimum.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Interactivity">
			<option name="Enable view edit">
				If checked all edit controls selected below will
				be rendered in the view. Unchecking this option disables all edit
				controls.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable title/subtitle edit controls">
				Renders a text box to change the chart title and
				subtitle in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable color mode edit">
				If checked, the color gradient can be toggled
				between continuous and discrete from within the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable 'show tool tips' option">
				If enabled, tool tips for the heatmap data cells
				and row labels can be toggled on/off from within the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable selection">
				When this option is checked, data points can be
				selected in the heatmap by activating the corresponding button and
				clicking on data cells. Extend the selection by holding down the
				Shift-key while clicking on points. The selection appears in an
				appended column of the data table.
			</option>
			<option name="Show reset selection button">
				If checked, a reset selection button will be
				displayed in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Selection column name">
				Name of the appended column containing boolean
				values to indicate, whether a data cell was selected in the view or
				not.
			</option>
			<option name="Publish selection events">
				If checked, notifies other interactive views when
				user changes the selection in the current view. See also "Subscribe
				to selection events".
			</option>
			<option name="Subscribe to selection events">
				If checked, the view reacts on notifications from
				other interactive views that the selection has been changed. See
				also "Publish selection events".
			</option>
			<option name="Enable 'show selected rows only' option">
				If selected, a "show selected rows only" checkbox
				will be displayed in the view's menu.
			</option>
			<option name="Show selected rows only">
				If enabled, only the selected rows will be
				displayed.
			</option>
			<option name="Subscribe to filter events">
				If checked, the view reacts when applied filters
				are changed.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable pagination">
				Enable or disable the pagination feature
				globally. When disabled the table is rendered whole on one page.
				When enabled use the options below to further refine the pagination
				settings.
			</option>
			<option name="Initial page size">
				Set the page size to be used on initial layout. A
				page size is defined as the number of rows the table displays on one
				page. If the page size change control is enabled the page length can
				be changed in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable page size change control">
				Enable or disable the control to change the page
				size interactively in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Selectable page sizes">
				Define a comma-separated list of allowed page
				sizes for the page size control.
			</option>
			<option name="Add &quot;All&quot; option to page sizes">
				When checked, an additional 'All' option will be
				available in the page size control.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable panning">
				Enable panning on the plot. To start panning
				click and drag the mouse. Note if panning and drag zooming is
				enabled, panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and
				dragging the mouse.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable zooming">
				Enable zooming on the plot using the mouse wheel.
			</option>
			<option name="Show zoom reset button">
				Renders a button to resize the plot to it's
				extends.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<interactiveView name="Heatmap">
		A heatmap representation of the
		input data table.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Input table" index="0">
			Input data table to display as
			a heatmap.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Image port" index="0">
			An SVG image representation
			of the view.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Output table" index="1">
			The input data table, with
			an appended selection column if selection is enabled.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>