<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./widget_credentials.png" type="Widget" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Credentials Widget</name>

	<shortDescription>
       Creates a Credentials input widget for use in components views. Outputs a credentials flow variable with a given value.
    </shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Creates a credentials input widget for use in components views. Outputs a credentials flow variable with a given
				value.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a
				flow variable 'customCSS' in the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available classes
				and their description on our <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">A descriptive label that will be shown in the view.</option>
		<option name="Description">Some lines of description that will be shown in the view,
			for instance by means of a tooltip.
		</option>
		<option name="Variable Name">Variable identifier.</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">Parameter identifier for external
			parameterization
			(e.g. batch execution).
		</option>
		<option name="Username">
			The username. 
		</option>
		<option name="Password">
			The password.
		</option>
		<option name="Prompt user name in widget view">
			Whether the username should be a separate field in the widget view, e.g. in KNIME WebPortal.
            If unset the username field will not be shown and the output will always the pre-configured username.
		</option>
        <option name="Save password in configuration (weakly encrypted)">
          Whether the password should be saved with the workflow. Note that, if saved, the password can be revealed
          with modest effort by looking at the encryption algorithm used in KNIME's (open) source code. If the password 
          is not saved (option not set) the user will be prompted for the password when the workflow is opened unless
          the node is already saved executed. In the latter case the password is not prompted assuming downstream 
          consumer nodes, e.g. a DB reader, are also executed and no longer need the credentials. In such cases 
          (resetting and) executing a downstream node will fail as the password is not part of the credentials object
          passed from this node into the workflow - a re-configuration of this node is required.
        </option>
        <option name="Use KNIME Server Login (when run on server)">
         If the node is executed as part of a job on the KNIME Server Web Portal the password is populated with the user
         credentials  the log-in user. 
         Please note that this option is not supported if your KNIME Server is configured to use single sign-on (SSO) via OAuth/OIDC.
        </option>
        <option name="Don't render input fields">
         When the server login and password are used it might be desirable to not display any input fields. When checking 
         this option the component will not display, but user name and password are still retrieved from server login credentials.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Credentials Widget">
		Displays a credentials input field which represents the string value.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
			Variable output (credentials) with the given variable defined.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
