<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../js.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>JavaScript Decision Tree View</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    A JavaScript based plot of the provided decision tree.
	</shortDescription>
		
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
    	    <p>A plot of the provided decision tree using a JavaScript based library. The view can be accessed either via
            the "interactive view" action on the executed node or in a KNIME Server web portal page. 
	       	</p>
	       	<p>The view shows a decision tree consisting of a number of nodes.
	       	The class label and the class counts displayed inside the nodes correspond to those of the training data.
	       	This especially means that the shown frequencies do not correspond to the rows used for selection (unless you use the full training dataset for selection). </p>
            <p>The configuration of the node lets you choose the number of rows to be used for selection and to enable certain 
            controls, which are then available in the view. This includes the possibility to set a title. Enabling or disabling these controls via the configuration
            dialog might not seem useful at first glance but has benefits when used in a web portal/wizard execution 
            where the end user has no access to the workflow itself.
            </p>
            <p>Additionally a static SVG image can be rendered, which is then made available at the first output port.</p>
            <p>Note, this node is currently under development. Future versions of the node might have more or changed functionality.</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Decision Tree Plot Options">
		    <option name="Hide in wizard">If the view should be hidden in the wizard execution.</option>
		    <option name="Create image at outport">If an image is supposed to be rendered during execute for the upper outport. Disable this option if image is not needed or creation is too time consuming.</option>
		    <option name="Expanded levels">Specifies how many levels of the tree are initially expanded. In case of a 0 only the root node is displayed, in case of a 1 also the children of the root are displayed, and so on.
		    (Initially disabled if a different node status is specified in the view and saved as new default.)</option>
		    <option name="Reset node status">If selected the node status is reset to the status corresponding to the specified expanded levels.
		    (Disabled if there is no node status from the view available.)</option>
		    <option name="Maximum number of rows">Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for selection.</option>
		    <option name="Selection column name">Name of the appended column containing boolean values to indicate, whether a point was selected in the view or not (disabled if no table is connected).</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="General Plot Options">
            <option name="Chart title" optional="true">The title of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no title will be shown.</option>
            <option name="Chart subtitle" optional="true">The subtitle of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no subtitle will be shown.</option>
            <option name="Display fullscreen button">Webportal option. If checked, a button is shown in the webportal to open the view in fullscreen mode.</option>
            <option name="Fill viewport">Webportal option. If checked, the view will fill all the space it gets in the webportal, even if the tree itself does not require the complete space.</option>
            <option name="Background color">The color of the background of the image.</option>
            <option name="Tree area color">The background color of the decision tree.</option>
            <option name="Node background color">The background color of the individual decision tree nodes.</option>
            <option name="Decimal digits">The number of decimals to show for numeric thresholds in the node conditions.</option>
            <option name="Decimal separator">The decimal separator to use for numeric thresholds in the node conditions.</option>
            <option name="Thousands separator">The separator to be used to separate thousands (i.e. " " corresponds to "100 000").</option>
            <option name="Custom prefix">A custom prefix for numbers displayed in node conditions.</option>
            <option name="Custom postfix">A custom postfix for numbers displayed in node conditions (i.e. to display currency).</option>
            <option name="Negative sign">A custom negative sign to use in node conditions.</option>
            <option name="Negative before string">A prefix that is used for negative numbers only. Inserted before the prefix.</option>
            <option name="Truncation limit">In the view long strings are abbreviated to avoid cluttering.
            The truncation limit specifies the maximal length of a string. For abbreviated strings a tooltip is added that displays the full string.</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="View Controls">
		    <option name="Enable view edit controls">If checked all edit controls selected below will be rendered in the view. Unchecking this option disables all edit controls.</option>
            <option name="Enable title edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart title in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable subtitle edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart subtitle in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable selection">Enables or disables the selection feature. When enabled, checking the selection checkbox in a decision tree node selects all rows that run through the decision tree node.
            The selection is propagated as an additional column in the output table of this node.</option>
            <option name="Display selection reset button">When enabled, a button is displayed in the view that allows to clear the current selection.</option>
            <option name="Publish selection events">When enabled, the view publishes the selections performed in it when it is run in the KNIME Server web portal.</option>
            <option name="Subscribe to selection events">When enabled, the view will react to selection events in the KNIME Server web portal</option>
            <option name="Enable zooming">Enable zooming on the plot using the mouse wheel.</option>
            <!--<option name="Show zoom reset button">Renders a button to resize the plot to it's extends.</option>
             -->
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<interactiveView name="Decision Tree View">
		Displays a tree plot of the provided decision tree.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Decision Tree">Decision tree to display.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Selection Data">Data which should be run through the decision tree.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Image">SVG image rendered by the JavaScript implementation of the decision tree plot.</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Input data and view selection">Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that represents the selection made in the decision tree view.</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>