<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./widget_value_filter.png" type="Widget" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Nominal Row Filter Widget</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Creates a value filter widget for use in components views. 
		Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the selected values of a chosen column.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Creates a value filter widget for use in components views.
				Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the selected values of a chosen column.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a
				flow variable
				'customCSS' in the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available classes
				and their description on
				our
				<a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>
				.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Control">
			<option name="Label">A descriptive label that will be shown in the view.</option>
			<option name="Description">Some lines of description that will be shown in the view,
				for instance by means of a tooltip.
			</option>
			<option name="Variable Name">Variable identifier.</option>
			<option name="Selection Type">
				Type of the selection panel.
			</option>
			<option name="Lock Column">
				If selected the column is locked and can not be selected from within the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Default Column">
				The column containing the values.
			</option>
			<option name="Default Values">
				The values that are selected by default.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable search">
				If selected a search field to filter the available columns will be rendered above the nominal row
				filter.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit height">
				By default the List, Twinlist and Checkboxes selection components adjust their height
				to display all possible choices. If this setting is enabled, the number of visible rows or items
				can be reduced to always be the amount set in 'Number of visible rows'.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of visible rows">
				The number of rows or items visible in selection component without a vertical scroll bar.
				Changing this value will also affect the component's height. Notice that for Twinlist the height cannot 
				be less than the overall height of the control buttons in the middle.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Re-execution">
			<option name="Re-execution on widget value change">
				If selected, widget emits reactivity events that trigger the
				re-execution of downstream nodes in a
				component composite view when
				its value changes. It allows users to create interactive Data Apps and visualizations.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Value Filter Widget">
		Displays a value filter panel.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table Input">
			Table containing the column(s) with values to be filtered.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered Table">
			Filtered table containing only rows with the selected values.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
