<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./configuration_column_select.png" type="QuickForm" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Column Selection Configuration</name>

	<shortDescription>
	   Provides a column selection configuration option to an encapsulating component's dialog. 
	   Outputs a string flow variable with the name of the selected column.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Provides a column selection configuration option to an encapsulating component's dialog. 
            Outputs a string flow variable with the name of the selected column.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
		  A descriptive label that will be shown in the dialog
		</option>
		<option name="Description">
		  Some lines of description that will be shown for instance in the node description of the component exposing a
		  dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">
		  Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution). 
		  This will also be the name of the exported flow variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Selection Type">
          Type of the selection panel.
        </option>
        <option name="Type Filter">
          Allows to restrict the selectable columns to a certain type. Furthermore it is possible to hide columns that don't have
          a domain (for nominal and numeric columns). By default all columns are included.
        </option>
        <option name="Default Value">
          The column that is selected by default.
        </option>
        <option name="Limit number of visible options">
          By default the List component adjusts its height to display all possible choices without a scroll bar. If the
          setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you have too many of them.
          The setting is available only for List selection type.</option>
        <option name="Number of visible options">
            A number of options visible in the List component without a vertical scroll bar. Changing this value will
            also affect the component's height. The setting is available only for List selection type.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table Input">
		  Table containing the columns to be selected.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
          Variable output (string) with the selected column name.
        </outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
