<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./configuration_string.png" type="Configuration" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>String Configuration</name>

	<shortDescription>
	   Provides a string configuration option to an encapsulating component's dialog. 
	   Outputs a string flow variable with the set value.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Outputs a string flow variable with a set value from a component's dialog.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
		  A descriptive label that will be shown in the dialog
		</option>
		<option name="Description">
		  Some lines of description that will be shown for instance in the node description of the component exposing a
		  dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution). 
		  This will also be the name of the exported flow variable.</option>
		<option name="Editor type">
          <i>Single-line</i> editor supports only one line text data and is represented with a text input component. 
          It also comes with a validation based on regular expressions.<br/>
          <i>Multi-line</i> editor supports many lines of text data and is represented with a text area component. 
          Its sizes can be parameterized (see the options below) and the scroll bar will automatically appear, if the 
          text is too long.          
        </option>
        <option name="Editor width">
          The width of the editor in number of characters per line.
        </option>
        <option name="Editor height">
          The height of the editor in number of text lines. Multi-line editor only.
        </option>
        <option name="Regular Expression">
            Regular expression defining valid values. Single-line editor only.
        </option>
        <option name="Validation Error Message">
            Message that will be shown if one of the values is not valid. The character ? will be replaced by the 
            invalid value. Single-line editor only.
        </option>
        <option name="Common Regular Expressions">
            A set of regular expression templates for common inputs. With the assign button you assign the 
            regular expression and the corresponding error message to be the current settings. Single-line editor only.
        </option>
        <option name="Default Value">
          The value that is selected by default.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
		  Variable output (string) with the given variable defined.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>text box</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
