<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./configuration_multiple_select.png" type="QuickForm" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Multiple Selection Configuration</name>

	<shortDescription>
	   Allows selecting multiple values from a list of strings in an encapsulating component's dialog. 
	   The selected values are returned as a data table and a string flow variable.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Allows selecting multiple values from a list of strings in an encapsulating component's dialog. 
       The selected values are returned as a data table and a string flow variable.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
		  A descriptive label that will be shown in the dialog
		</option>
		<option name="Description">
		  Some lines of description that will be shown for instance in the node description of the component exposing a
		  dialog.
		</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">
		  Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution). 
		  This will also be the name of the exported flow variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Selection Type">
		  The type of the selection element. This can be either check boxes with a vertical or horizontal layout, a 
		  List or a Twinlist.
		</option>
        <option name="Possible Choices">
          The possible choices, each line is one possible value.
        </option>
        <option name="Default Values">
          Values selected by default.
        </option>
        <option name="Limit number of visible options">
          By default the List and Twinlist components adjust their height to display all possible choices without a
          scroll bar. If the setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you
          have too many of them. The setting is available only for List or Twinlist selection type.</option>
        <option name="Number of visible options">
            A number of options visible in the List or Twinlist component without a vertical scroll bar. 
            Changing this value will also affect the component's height. Notice that for Twinlist the height cannot 
            be less than the overall height of the control buttons in the middle. The setting is available only for 
            List or Twinlist selection type.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Selected Value Table">
          Table output holding the selected choices in one column with the given parameter name as column name.
        </outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
