<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./widget_column_filter.png" type="Widget" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Column Filter Widget</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Creates a column filter widget for use in components views. 
		Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the selected columns.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Creates a column filter widget for use in components views. 
				Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the selected columns.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a
				flow variable 'customCSS' in the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available classes
				and their description on our <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Control">
			<option name="Label">A descriptive label that will be shown in the view.</option>
			<option name="Description">Some lines of description that will be shown in the view,
				for instance by means of a tooltip.
			</option>
			<option name="Variable Name">Variable identifier.</option>
			<option name="Default Values">
				The columns that are selected by default.
			</option>
			<option name="Limit number of visible options">
				By default the filter component adjusts its height to display all possible choices without a scroll bar. If 
				the setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you have too many of
				them.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of visible options">
				A number of options visible in the filter component without a vertical scroll bar. Changing this value will
				also affect the component's height. Notice that the height cannot be less than the overall height of the 
				control buttons in the middle.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Re-execution">
			<option name="Re-execution on widget value change">
				If selected, widget emits reactivity events that trigger the
				re-execution of downstream nodes in a component composite view when
				its value changes. It allows users to create interactive Data Apps and visualizations.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Column Filter Widget">
		Displays a column filter panel.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table Input">
			Table containing the columns to be filtered.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered Table">
			Filtered table containing only the selected columns.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
