<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./quickform_column_filter.png" type="QuickForm"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Column Filter</name>

    <shortDescription>
      Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the selected columns.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Takes a data table and returns a filtered data table with only the 
              selected columns. The selection can also be controlled from a 
              quickfrom (WebPortal).
            </p>
            <p>
            The node supports custom CSS styling. 
            You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a flow variable 'customCSS' 
            in the node configuration dialog. 
            You will find the list of available classes and their description on our <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Label">
          A descriptive label that will be shown in, for instance the WebPortal.
        </option>
        <option name="Description">
          Some lines of description that will be shown in the remote control 
          form, for instance by means of a tooltip.
        </option>
        <option name="Hide in Dialog">
          If the setting should be hidden in a wrapped metanode dialog.
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Name">
          Variable identifier.
        </option>
        <option name="Parameter Name">Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution).</option>
        <!--
        <option name="Selection Type">
          Type of the selection panel.
        </option>
        -->
        <option name="Default Values">
          The columns that are selected by default.
        </option>
        <option name="Limit number of visible options">
          By default the filter component adjusts its height to display all possible choices without a scroll bar. If the setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you have too many of them.</option>
        <option name="Number of visible options">
            A number of options visible in the filter component without a vertical scroll bar. Changing this value will also affect the component's height. Notice that the height cannot be less than the overall height of the control buttons in the middle.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Column filter">
		Select multiple columns.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Table Input" index="0">Table containing the columns.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered Table">Filtered table containing only the selected columns.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
