<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./widget_value_select.png" type="Widget" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Value Selection Widget</name>

	<shortDescription>
       Creates a value selection widget for use in components views. 
       Outputs a string flow variable with the name of the selected value.
    </shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Creates a value selection widget for use in components views. 
                Outputs a string flow variable with the name of the selected value.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a
				flow variable 'customCSS' in the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available classes
				and their description on our <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">
          A descriptive label that will be shown in the view.
        </option>
        <option name="Description">
          Some lines of description that will be shown in the view, for instance by means of a tooltip.
        </option>
        <option name="Variable Name">
          Variable identifier.
        </option>
        <option name="Selection Type">
          Type of the selection panel.
        </option>
        <!-- <option name="Column Type">
          The type of columns that can be selected.
        </option> -->
        <option name="Lock Column">
          If selected the column is locked and can not be selected from within the view.
        </option>
        <option name="Default Column">
          The column containing the values.
        </option>
        <option name="Default Value">
          The value that is selected by default.
        </option>
        <option name="Limit number of visible options">
          By default the List component adjusts its height to display all possible choices without a scroll bar. If the
          setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you have too many of them.
          The setting is available only for List selection type.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of visible options">
            A number of options visible in the List component without a vertical scroll bar. Changing this value will
            also affect the component's height. The setting is available only for List selection type.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Value Selection Widget">
		Displays a column selection panel.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table Input">
          Table containing the values to be selected.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">
         Variable output (string) with the selected value name. Additionally the chosen column name is output as a 
         separate flow variable.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
