<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../js.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>JavaScript Lift Chart</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    A lift chart using a JavaScript based charting library.
	</shortDescription>
		
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Creates a lift chart. Additionally, a chart for the cumulative 
        percent of responses captured is shown. A lift chart is used to evaluate 
        a predictive model. The higher the lift (the difference between the "lift" line 
        and the base line), the better performs the predictive model.
        The lift is the ratio between the results obtained with and without the 
        predictive model. 
        It is calculated as number of positive hits (e .g. responses) divided by
        the average number of positives without model.
        The data table must have a column containing probabilities and a nominal 
        column, containing the actual labels.
        At first, the data is sorted by probability, divided into deciles,
        then the actual labels are counted and the average rate is calculated.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Data Options">
	        <option name="Response Column">Nominal column containing the actual labels, e. g. if a person responded</option>
	        <option name="Probability Column">Numeric column containing the predicted score in probabilities of the model</option>
	        <option name="Positive label (hits)">The label for a positive value (hit).</option>
	        <option name="Interval width in %">The width in which the data is separated before counting.</option>
	        <option name="Ignore missing values">If checked, the missing values in Probability columns will be ignored without a warning message. 
	        Otherwise, they will be sorted to the end of the curves with a corresponding warning message.<br/>
	        Missing values in Response column are ignored in any case.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="General Plot Options">
            <option name="Create image at outport">If an image is supposed to be rendered during execute for the upper outport. Disable this option if image is not needed or creation is too time consuming.</option>
            <option name="Width of image (in px)">The width of the generated SVG image.</option>
            <option name="Height of image (in px)">The height of the generated SVG image.</option>
            <option name="Line width (in px)">The width of the shown lines.</option>
            <option name="Smoothing">The smoothing algorithm for the shown lines.</option>

            <option name="Resize view to fill window">Setting this option resizes the view to the available area of the window. If disabled the view size is static according to the set width and height.</option>
            <option name="Background color">The color of the background of the image.</option>
            <option name="Data area color">The background color of the data area, within the axes.</option>
            <option name="Show grid">If an additional grid is being rendered at the axes tick positions.</option>
            <option name="Grid color">The color of the grid.</option>
            <option name="Show warnings in view">If checked, warning messages will be displayed in the view when they occur.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Axis Configuration">
            <option name="Label for x-axis" optional="true">The label for the x-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
            <option name="Label for y-axis" optional="true">The label for the y-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
            <option name="Show color legend">Switches the legend on/off. The legend shows the mapping between colors used in the view and the respective column names.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="View Controls">
            <option name="Enable view edit controls">If checked all edit controls selected below will be rendered in the view. Unchecking this option disables all edit controls.</option>
            <option name="Enable title edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart title in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable subtitle edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart subtitle in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable label edit for x-axis">Renders a text box to change x-axis label in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable label edit for y-axis">Renders a text box to change y-axis label in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable toggle between views">Renders a control to switch between Lift Chart and Cumulative Gain Chart modes.</option>
            <option name="Enable selection of smoothing">Renders a selector of smoothing algorithm.</option>
        </tab>
        
	</fullDescription>
	
	<interactiveView name="Lift Chart">
		Displays a lift chart visualization.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Display data">Data table with data to display.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Image">SVG image rendered by the JavaScript implementation of the lift chart.</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Input data and view selection">Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that represents the selection made in the lift chart view.</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>