<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../js.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>JavaScript Table View</name>
    <shortDescription>Displays data in a table view.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Displays data in an HTML table view. The view offers several interactive features, as well as the possibility to select rows.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
        	<description>
        		<p>General view and display options.</p>
        	</description>
        	<option name="Hide in wizard">
        		If checked the view will be hidden in the wizard execution.
        	</option>
            <option name="No. of rows to display">
    	        Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for this visualization.
        	</option>
	        <option name="Title" optional="true">
	        	An optional title to be displayed above the table. Leave blank if no title is desired.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Subtitle" optional="true">
	        	An optional subtitle to be displayed above the table. Leave blank if no subtitle is desired.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Display row colors">
	        	Enable or disable the display of row colors. Colors can be assigned e.g. with the Color Manager node and will be rendered as a colored square next to the row keys.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Display row keys">
	        	Enable or disable the display of row keys. When enabled row keys will be rendered in a separate column.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Display row indices">
	        	Enable or disable the display of row indices. When enabled row indices will be rendered in a separate column.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Display column headers">
	        	Enable or disable the display of column headers. When disabled sorting on columns will not be functional.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Columns to display">
	        	Select the columns to be included in the table view.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Interactivity">
        	<description>
        		The JavaScript Table View allows for several ways of interactivity. Please use the options below to configure which features will be activated on the view and further configuration of interactive properties.
        	</description>
        	<option name="Enable pagination">
        		Enable or disable the pagination feature globally. When disabled the table is rendered whole on one page. When enabled use the options below to further refine the pagination settings.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Initial page size">
        		Set the page size to be used on initial layout. A page size is defined as the number of rows the table displays on one page. If the page size change control is enabled the page length can be changed in the view.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable page size change control">
        		Enable or disable the control to change the page size interactively in the view.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Selectable page sizes">
        		Define a comma-separated list of allowed page sizes for the page size control.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Add 'All' option to sizes">
        		When checked, an additional 'All' option will be available in the page size control.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable selection">
        		If checked a separate column containing checkboxes is rendered in the view. The selection, when applied, will be represented in the output table as a new boolean column.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Selection column name">
        		The name of the boolean column containing the selection.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable searching">
        		Enable or disable the global search field.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable search for individual columns">
        		Enable or disable search fields on each individual column.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable sorting on columns">
        		Enable or disable the sorting functionality for each column.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable 'Clear Sorting' button">
        		When checked, a button is displayed above the table, to clear any sorting that is applied to the table and restore the row order to the initial state.
        	</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Formatters">
        	<description>
        		The JavaScript Table View maps the KNIME table data types to types in JavaScript. The types that can be displayed are:
        		<ul>
        			<li>Boolean</li>
        			<li>Number (double, integer, etc.)</li>
        			<li>String</li>
        			<li>Date and Time</li>
        			<li>PNG</li>
        			<li>SVG</li>
        		</ul>
        		All other data types will be treated as UNKNOWN types. These are tried to be displayed by extracting their respective standard string representation.<br/><br/>
        		If you wish to customize the format for certain data types you can use the following options. For unknown types the formatting has to be applied in preceding nodes.
        	</description>
        	<option name="Global date format">
        		A global format, which is applied to all date/time cells. To format the string the framework Moment.js is used. For information on available format options and tokens please see the <a href="http://momentjs.com/docs/#/displaying/format/"> moment.js documentation</a>.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable global number format (double cells)">
        		If checked the option beneath will be applied to all columns of type <i>Double</i>.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Decimal places">
        		If number format is enabled use this value to restrict the display of decimal places for double columns in the table view.
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <interactiveView name="JavaScript Table View">
        Displays the data in a table view.
    </interactiveView>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input to display">
            Input table to display.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Input data and view selection">
            Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that represents the selection made in the table view.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>