<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./quickform_strsel.png" type="QuickForm" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Multiple Selections</name>
	<shortDescription>Allows selecting multiple values from a list of String which is returned as a data table and String flow variable.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Allows selecting multiple values from a list of String which is returned as a data table and String flow
				variable. The value can also be controlled from a QuickForm (KNIME WebPortal).</p>
				<p>
            The node supports custom CSS styling. 
            You can simply put CSS rules into a single string and set it as a flow variable 'customCSS' 
            in the node configuration dialog. 
            You will find the list of available classes and their description on our <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
            </p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Label">A descriptive label that will be shown in, for instance the web port.</option>
		<option name="Description">Some lines of description that will be shown in the remote control
			form, for instance by means of a tooltip.</option>
        <option name="Hide in Dialog">
          If the setting should be hidden in the sub node dialog.
        </option>
		<option name="Variable Name">Variable identifier.</option>
		<option name="Parameter Name">Parameter identifier for external parameterization (e.g. batch execution).</option>
		<option name="Selection Type">The type of the selection element. This can be either check boxes with a vertical or horizontal layout, a list or a twinlist.</option>
		<option name="Possible Choices">The possible choices, each line is one possible value.</option>
		<option name="Default Values">Values selected by default.</option>
		<option name="Limit number of visible options">
          By default the List and Twinlist components adjust their height to display all possible choices without a scroll bar. If the setting is enabled, you will be able to limit the number of visible options in case you have too many of them. The setting is available only for List or Twinlist selection type.</option>
        <option name="Number of visible options">
            A number of options visible in the List or Twinlist component without a vertical scroll bar. Changing this value will also affect the component's height. Notice that for Twinlist the height cannot be less than the overall height of the control buttons in the middle. The setting is available only for List or Twinlist selection type.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Multiple selection">
    	Select multiple options.
    </interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable Output">Table output holding the selected choices in one column with the Variable Name as column name.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
